Guide to the Radio TV Services Records, circa 1937 - 2008
Duke University. University Archives
- Film and Video circa 1937-1987 and undated
  - Film, Unnumbered 10 and 12 inch reels, circa 1948-1965, undated
    - Duke Band, 1952, 1 film reel: 12 inch. (Box 18)
      Band Day (W. & L. Game)
      Tennessee-Duke (Pre-game to half time)
      N. C. State at Raleigh
      Virginia at Charlottesville
      '52 Homecoming
      '52 Duke-Georgia Tech (Pre-game and half time crowning of Queen.)
      '52 Duke-Wake Forest
    - Marine Laboratory Kodachrome Original, undated, 1 film on core, no reel, in 10 inch can.
    - Marine Lab Orig Optical Soundtrack Negative, undated, 1 film on core, no reel, in 10 inch can.
    - Marine Laboratory, undated, 1 film reel: 10 inch.
    - Quest Without End, 1957, 1 film on core, no reel, in 10 inch can.
      Duplication Master: Beta SP. UA88-57-2
      Reference Copy: VHS. UA88-57-2
      Quest Without End was produced by Alumni Affairs and consists largely of set pieces and staged scenes of campus life. John Koskinen, Chair of the Board of Trustees, appears.
    - Quest Without End, 1957, 1 film reel: 12-inch.
    - Quest Without End Orig. Koda and Ansco, 1957, 1 film on core, no reel, in 10 inch can.
    - Quest Without End Track Neg., 1957, 1 film on core, no reel, in 10 inch can.
    - Response to Our Challenge, 1965, 1 film on core, no reel, in 10 inch can.
    - This is Duke, 1954, 1 film reel: sd., col.; 12 inch. (Box 19)
      Duplication Master: Beta SP. UA88-57-1
      Reference Copy: VHS. UA88-57-1
      Produced for Alumni Affairs, this promotional film is presented as a tour of the campus by a student. It contains footage of campus life, religious activities, commencement, homecoming, Joe College Weekend, classrooms, laboratories, the hospital, professional schools, and Duke Forest. A section towards the end has footage of many senior administrators.
      From a note in the University Archives collection file: The film This is Duke University was a 27-minute film done in the 1950s. Fred Whitener photographed most of the film and produced it. Harry Owen did the sound recording and titles. A mechanical engineering student (an announcer for WDBS, who had a good deep voice) did the narration. The film had a musical background. Allan Bone selected the music from records and it was dubbed with narration. Engineering did the sound recording on the equipment in the photograph. The film was shown all over the world, including on cruise ships. The total costs of this first film with sound, including a trip to N.Y. by Fred Whitenener and Harry Owen, was less than $1,000. Dr. Owen said it should be copied to video tape. Harry Owen, 6/12/85.
      Alumni Register, Sept. 1954, pp. 16-17. A copy of the article is in Box 19, Folder 11.
    - This is Duke, 1954, 1 film on core, no reel, in 10-inch can.
    - This is Duke University, 1954 Track - Pos, 1 film reel: 12 inch.
    - World of Miracles: Institute of Science and Math, circa 1950-1960, 1 film reel: sd., col.; 12 inch.
    - World of Miracles, undated, 1 film reel: sd., b&w; 12 inch.
    - World of Miracles IR Orig. Koda + POS Track, undated, 1 film on core, no reel, in 10-inch can.
    - World of Miracles Track Dupe, undated, 1 film on core, no reel, in 10-inch can.
    - Unknown, undated, 1 film reel: 12 inch.
  - Film, Unnumbered 3 inch reels, circa 1948-1965, undated (Box 20)
    All of the film in this sub-series is 16mm on 3-inch reels. These reels seem to have been packed in this box simply because they were all the same size. Most of them appear to have been shot before the creation of the Radio TV Services, so it is assumed that they were inherited from some other organization.
    Some of the subjects depicted include homecoming, Joe College, the Marine Laboratory, Duke Gardens, football, other athletics, commencement, various campus scenes, and the Epoch Campaign Announcement.
    When they were acquired by the Archives, many of these reels were undated. Most of them, however, are in their original film manufacturer's boxes. Sometimes the box has a postmark on it, indicating when the film was mailed after being processed. In this case, the postmark is used to date the film if there is no other indication of date. Most boxes also have an expiration date-a Develop Before or Process Before date. When there is no shoot date or postmark, the expiration date is used to date the film, under the assumption that it provides a general time period in which the film was shot.
    Films are arranged chronologically by shoot date, postmark, or expiration date, followed by films for which no date could be determined. These are arranged in alphabetical order by title.
    - Dance Scenes, Apr. 1946
    - Old homecoming scenes taken from yr. at Duke, 1948
    - Unknown, Exp. Date: Mar. 1950
    - Grad Dance. Band & Jean [Levo?], 1951
    - Joe College Parade, 1951
    - Pics of Coombs, Armed Forces, May 1952
    - May Festival, 1952
    - Marine Lab, Jan. 1953
    - Aerials (left over) Jumpy, June 1953
    - Garden shots, June 1953
    - Under-Exposed. Use as leader, Exp. Date: Apr. 1954
    - Football, July 1954
    - Band, D. Perdue, Pre-Game, Oct. 1954
    - Marching Band, Oyster Bowl, Norfolk, Va., Nov. 1954
    - Athletics at Duke University, Dec. 1954
    - Football Crowd Scenes, 1954
    - Half Time I, Jan. 1955
    - Football Practice, Sept. 1955
    - Commencement, 1956
    - Garden III, July 10, 1957
    - Dozier, Jordan, Dukes, Cleland, Marker, Exp. Date: May 1958
    - Unknown, Exp. Date: May 1958
    - Alumni Reunion Luncheon, June 1958
    - Garden, Apr. 26, 1959
    - Joe College Parade, May 1, 1959
    - Chapel Shots, 1959
    - Engineer Show, 1959
    - Freshman Wk '59 Inside Shots, 1959
    - Freshman Wk '59 Outside Shots, 1959
    - H C Show, 1959
    - Unknown, Exp. Date: Jan. 1959
    - Unknown, circa Feb. 1960
    - Law Interior, Mar. 1960
    - Nursing School Corridor, Apr. 1960
    - Symbols, Law Class, May 1960
    - Unknown, May 1960
    - Chronicle, July 1960
    - Beaufort, July 1960
    - Beaufort, Aug. 1960
    - Aerials, 1960
    - Beaufort 2, 1960
    - Campus Scenes, 1960
    - Chapel Windows, 1960
    - Forestry, Tree Climbers, 1960
    - GE College Bowl, 1960
    - Military Revue, Order of Chair, 1960
    - Order of Chair, Construction Scenes, 1960
    - Unknown, 1960
    - Unknown, 1960
    - Willie Grad Scenes, 1960
    - Studying after Basketball Game, Exp. Date: Jan. 1960
    - [Neredran?], Exp. Date: Mar. 1960
    - Rare Book Room, Whitman Collection, Spanish Dancers, Exp. Date: Mar. 1960
    - Basketball, Outside Gym - night scenes, Exp. Date: Mar. 1960
    - Commencement, Exp. Date: Apr. 1960
    - Original site of West Campus before construction, Exp. Date: June 1960
    - Faculty Club, Exp. Date: Oct. 1960
    - Banquet, Exp. Date: Nov. 1960
    - Mech. & E.E., Exp. Date: Nov. 1960
    - Modern Dance, Medical Research, Exp. Date: Nov. 1960
    - Unknown, Jan. 1961
    - Gown Fitting, 1961
    - Unknown, Exp. Date: Jan. 1961
    - Unknown, Exp. Date: Jan. 1961
    - Unknown, Exp. Date: Feb. 1961
    - Debate Team, Winter Chapel, Exp. Date: Mar. 1961
    - Sidewalk Art, Pick up man, Law Ext., Exp. Date: Mar. 1961
    - Symphony, Exp. Date: Mar. 1961
    - J. B. Duke Plaque, Exp. Date: Apr. 1961
    - Chapel inside, Choir, East Dorm, Exp. Date: May 1961
    - Practice - Rochester & T. Mooyman, Exp. Date: July 1961
    - Univ. Outtakes, Exp. Date: Apr. 1962
    - Law School Left Overs, Exp. Date: May 1963
    - Football: Florida vs. Duke, Sept. 12, 1970
    - Football: Duke - Virginia, Sept. 26, 1970
    - Football: Duke - West Virginia, Oct. 10, 1970
    - Football: Duke - N. C. State, Oct. 17, 1970
      A mimeograph listing scenes from this film is in Folder 9, Box 20. Players mentioned are Leo Hart, Dan Phelan, Billy Thompson, Steve Jones, Dave Wright, Rich Searl, Dick Biddle, Ernie Jackson, and Tom Ussery.
    - Football: Duke - South Carolina, Nov. 14, 1970
      A mimeograph listing scenes from this film is included in Folder 9, Box 20. Players mentioned are Art Bosetti, Leo Hart, Wes Chesson, Bob Parrish, Brad Evans, Bill Baker, and Dick Biddle.
    - Football: Duke - North Carolina, Nov. 21, 1970
    - Campus Scenes, circa 1970
    - Football, Sept. 30, 1971
      The date above is written on the film's leader; however, Duke did not play a game on Sept. 30, 1971. Possibly this film is of Duke's Sept. 25 game against Virginia, or of Duke's Oct. 30 game against Georgia Tech.
    - Epoch Campaign Announcement: T. Sanford, J. A. Jones, Alex McMahon, Sept. 27, 1973
      Duplication Master: Beta SP. UA88-57-10
    - 50th Anniversary Convocation Processional with Duke statue & pickets, Apr. 12, 1975
      Duplication Master: Beta SP. UA88-57-11
      Highlights of the 50th Anniversary Convocation Processional appear on Duplication Master: Beta SP. UA88-57-12
      Highlights of the 50th Anniversary Convocation Processional appear on Reference Copy: VHS. UA88-57-12
    - 50th Anniversary Graduation, May 1975
    - Removing Fossils & Rock, 1975
    - Egg Drop, Nov. 13, 1979
    - 2nd Ed. Cuts 1, undated
    - 2nd Ed. II, undated
    - Campus, undated
    - Campus Scenes, undated
    - Campus Scenes, undated
    - Card Tricks, undated
    - Duke 140 Old Orig., undated
    - Duke Film, undated
    - Football, undated
    - Freshman Reception, undated
    - Glee Club, undated
    - Good campus (color), students studying, undated
    - Home Security Commercials, undated
    - Home Security Commercials, undated
    - Law N.C., Student & Dr. Hoover, undated
    - Law School, Grad PhD exam, Jean in library stacks, undated
    - Old Homecoming Scenes, undated
    - Unknown, undated
    - Unknown, undated
    - Unknown, undated
  - Video, 1981-1987, undated (Box 21)
    Subjects include the U.S.S. Monitor, lemurs, the proposed Nixon library at Duke, Terry Sanford, and an Easter service at the chapel.
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Aquanautics Corporation: The Artificial Gill, undated, 1 videocassette (U-matic) (21:00).
    - Bamboo Lemurs, 1987, 1 videocassette (U-matic) (approx. 10:00).
    - Duke University 1982-1983 ACC School, Profile & Footage used to produce that Profile for Raycom / Jefferson Productions Sports Network, Apr. 16, 1983, 1 videocassette (U-matic).
    - Duke University Chapel Easter Worship Service, Apr. 11, 1982, 1 videocassette (U-matic).
    - Monitor Search Seq., undated, 1 video reel (2:29): 6 1/2-inch reel, 2 inch tape.
    - NBC Nightly News: Nixon Library, Aug. 27, 1981, 1 videocassette (U-matic).
    - NBC Nightly News: Nixon Library Controversy, Aug. 27, 1981, 1 videocassette (U-matic) (2:12).
    - New Duke Scholarships and Grants, undated, 1 videocassette (U-matic) (1:59).
    - 60 Minutes: Terry Sanford, Jan. 25, 1981, 1 videocassette (U-matic) (52:00).
    - Student Life in the United States, Apr. 20, 1981, 1 videocassette (U-matic) (29:05).
- Additions [unprocessed]
  - UA2008-0048, 1990-2005, 5 boxes
    Accession contains video tape (mostly VHS, 2 DVDs, some BetaMax) of events related to Duke occurring both on and off campus. Some topics include NC People (Nan Keohane, Keith Brodie, Richard Brodhead, Terry Sanford); history of Duke stone; Duke Primate Center; Graduate 1997; and NCAA championship bonfire.
  - UA2008-0065, 1993-2008
    Accession contains cassettes, mini dics, CDs, and DVDs of events related to Duke and Duke personalities. Some subjects include convocations, baccalaureate services, graduations, tributes (John Burness, Jerry Black). Noted speakers include Pres. Brodhead, Pres. Keohane, John Hope Frankin, Cokie Roberts, Janet Reno, George Bush, etc.